Against this foe,
there shall be no playing by ear!
(自来也)コイツを相手に
様子見はない！
I'm coming at you with full force!
最初から全力でいくからのぉ！
(自来也)仙人モードを使う！
I'm using the Honored Sage Mode!
(ガマケン)まさか！ では…。
What?! You don't mean...?!
Yes indeed.
そのまさか。
あの二大仙人を口寄せする。
I'm summoning the two great sages!
だが あの２人を呼ぶまで
ちっとばかり時間がかかる。
However, it's going to take some time
to summon the two of them.
その間
この手を離すことはできん。
And I cannot release my hands
during that time.
頼む！ それまで
時間を稼いでくれ！
I'm counting on you.
Buy me some time until then!
わかった。
不器用なりにやってみよう。
All right. Clumsy as I am, I shall try.
消えおったか。 厄介だの。
He vanished. What a bother...
どこで見つけてきたんだ
あんなのを。
Where in the world did he find
such a creature?
消えたとあっては
結界戦術でやるしかないの。
Now that he's made himself invisible,
we've got to use Barrier Battle Arts.
う～む！ 戦いにくいな。
Hmm... He's a hard one to battle.
(ペイン)確か あれは➡
As I recall...
This is a barrier ninjutsu that senses and
alerts any intrusion across its boundary.
足を踏み入れたら
感知するタイプの結界忍術。
ならば…。
In that case...
結界を見て
攻撃力の強いのに変えてきたか！
He saw the barrier and switched
to a strong offensive critter!
ガマケンさん！
おう！ 不器用ながら➡
Mister Gamaken!
Right! Clumsy as I am, here we go!
お控えなすってもらいやす！
器用じゃねえか。
(ガマケン)いえいえ。
You're quite skilled!
Not at all... I am clumsy.
自分は 不器用なもんで…。
なに!?
What?!
Wh-What is this?!
な… なんじゃ こりゃ!?
うわっ！
うっ！
(自来也)大丈夫か？ ガマケンさん。
Are you okay, Mister Gamaken?
できれば もう少し
うまくやれんもんかの？
You think you could do this
a bit smoother?
自分 不器用なもんで…。
But I am clumsy...
コイツら 殴るたびに増えとるの。
They seem to multiply each time
you clobber them...
もはや 何ものかすら わからん。
I don't even have a clue what it is...
自ら 増幅口寄せの術に縛られた
ワン公か？
Are the doggies bound to
a self-replicating summoning jutsu?!
(自来也)とにかく
いったん 場を変えんと…。
In any case,
we'd better move from this spot.
１匹ずつ 殺る。
狭い場所に誘いこむぞ！
We'll kill one dog at a time!
Let's lure them into a small space.
おう！
Right!
《ペイン : どうやら 術の肝はあれか》
So that's the center of the jutsu...
まいた… かのぉ？
Were we able to lose it...?
That should buy us some time.
時間は稼… げんか！
Or not!
もう 挟まれてしもうた。
We're surrounded already!
来る！ また バラけるぞ。
Incoming! And they're going
to split up again!
上だ！
Above you!
(自来也)これじゃ
きりがないのぉ…。
There's no end to this.
(ガマケン)がんばっては
いるんですがね…。
I am  trying my best...
If they keep dividing,
no matter how hard we strike them,
叩いても 叩いても
無尽蔵に分裂するんじゃ➡
it's a waste of our energy.
努力のしがいがないのぉ…。
もう 来よったか
このワンパターンめが！
Here already?
Damn persistent dogs!
この～！
Stupid little...!
大丈夫かのぉ!? あっ！
Are you all right?!
ガマケンさん！
Mister Gamaken!
やっぱり
自分 不器用ですから…。
I really am...
clumsy...
ガマケンさんが動けないんではのぉ…。
If you can't move, Mister Gamaken...
then there's no time to summon
the two great sages.
二大仙人様を呼んどる暇はないか。
お手上げじゃ。
I give up.
しかし よくも
これだけ 増えたものよ。 フフフ…。
But I'm amazed
there're so many of them...
だが 妙木山の大蝦蟇にかかりゃ
これくらい ひと飲みよ！
But against the Great Toad
of Mount Myoboku,
you're all nothing but a small snack!
Honored Sage Mode!
消えた。
犬もろとも ひとまず逃げたか。
Gone... Along with the dogs.
So he's escaped for now.
(自来也)逃げとりゃせん！
I haven't escaped!
長門 まだ詰めが甘いのぉ。
Nagato, you're still a novice.
後ろをとられるとはな！
Leaving your back open for an attack!
お前も影分身か！
You're a Shadow Clone too?!
Yes, but that's not all.
そう それだけじゃない。
同時に… 口寄せ！
At the same time... Summoning Jutsu!
しまった!!
Damn it!
《ダメか…》
It's no good...
ガマケンさん！
Mister Gamaken!
なんじゃ？
What?
おっとっと…。
Whoa...
どわっ!!
しめた！
Yes!
お役御免！
You're relieved from duty!
やったわい… えっ？
I did it!
Huh?
《よくも まあ 次から次へと…。
It's one thing after another...
だが もうちょっとだ。
But I'm almost there.
じゃから ここで
やめるわけにはいかんのだが…。
So I can't quit now, but...
来よった！》
Incoming!
なっ… 速い！
Wha--?! So fast!!
すまんのぉ。 遅くなった。
Sorry I'm late.
お疲れさん。
Good work!
ハア… ハア… ハア…。
まったく 術者を攻撃しようにも
消えてしまっては手が出せん。
I want to attack the caster,
but I need to be able to see him!
ガマケンさんは
何かおかしいとは思わんか？
Don't you think something
is strange, Mister Gamaken?
じ… 自分… 不器用なもんで
よくわからんですが…。
I-I am...
too clumsy to understand
what you mean.
He who possessed the same pupils
as the Sage of the Six Paths,
六道仙人と
同じ目を持っていたあヤツは➡
教えた術を
すべてマスターしたどころか➡
not only mastered every jutsu
I taught him...
１人では
本来ありえぬ チャクラの性質変化。
he demonstrated the ability to achieve
all six changes in Chakra Nature.
６通りの
すべてをやって見せた。
For a single person to do so
is unheard of.
主流忍術すべてに
精通した力を持ち➡
He was well versed in
all the mainstream ninjutsu...
10歳にして
あらゆる術を使いこなした。
and mastered them by the time
he was ten years old.
《なのになぜ…》
But why...?
《なぜ口寄せの術しか
使ってこない？
Why is he only using
the Summoning Jutsu against me?!
Does he think I am beneath
the need for direct confrontation?
自分が
戦うまでもないということか？》
クッ！
ガマケンさん もう大丈夫だ！
Mister Gamaken! You've done enough!
I've got it from here, go home!
あとはわしがやる！ 戻ってくれ！
わかった すまぬ。
All right. Thanks.
(シマ)小僧 おぬしゃ 何でこが～な
騒がしいとこば～にしか➡
Lad! Why do you always summon us
in such touchy situations like this?!
口寄せせんのじゃ。
ブン太が怒るのも
無理ねえわいそりゃ。
It's no wonder Bunta gets so mad!
(フカサク)
アハハハッ そう言うなや母ちゃん。
Aw c'mon, Ma.
Naturally, Jiraiya-boy has his reasons.
自来也ちゃんにも
事情いうのがあらな～や。
そりゃ…。
父ちゃんは黙っときんさい！
You be quiet, Pa!
まったくもう！
お久しぶりにこんなんで➡
It's been a while,
申し訳ありませんのぉ。
頭に ねえさん。
and I do apologize for calling you
under these circumstances, Boss, Ma'am.
しっかし小僧 おぬしは
女子にモテんなるいうて➡
But lad... I thought you said
you hated that form,
saying it would make you unpopular
with the ladies!
その体を
嫌がっとったんじゃろうがの。
そうも言って
られなくなりましてのぉ。
I can't afford to be particular right now.
なにせ相手が輪廻眼でして。
After all, my foe has the Rinnegan.
おお 六道の眼か。
Ah...the Pupils of Six Paths?!
ホンマにおったんかいな そんなんが。
Someone actually possesses
such an eye?
まあ それなら仕方もなかろうが。
Well then, you had no choice.
(フカサク)そろそろ１人で
仙人モードに変身できるように➡
You gotta start being able to go into
Sage Mode by yourself, Jiraiya-boy.
なれんといけんで 自来也ちゃん。
お二人に比べたら
まだまだペーペーですんでのぉ。
Compared to you,
I'm still just a novice.
どうか少しの間 お力添えを。
So please lend me your aid
for just a little while...
では いきますぞ。
Shall we begin?
《あれほど苦労して
呼び出したのが あのガマ２匹。
He went through all that just
to summon those two toads...?
いや先生自身に変化が起きている。
No, there is a transformation going on
in Sensei himself.
フン。 大蛇丸にしろ自来也にしろ➡
Humph, whether it's Orochimaru or Jiraiya,
the Sannin each have unique powers.
三忍は 独特の力を使うな》
(フカサク)で どこにおるんなら？
その六道の眼は。
And? Where is the one with
the Pupils of Six Paths?
(シマ)
歳で目がわるうなっとるけんのぉ。
Your eyes must be degrading with age.
いや 透明化する
口寄せ動物のなかに入って➡
No. He's hidden himself inside
a summoning creature
that can make itself invisible.
姿を隠しております。
だとすると
カメレオン類のヤツらじゃのぉ。
It's gotta be one of them
chameleon species.
一応 探知結界は
張っとるんですがのぉ。
I have erected a probe barrier.
そんなんでは ラチがあかん！
That won't do any good!
生物探知でこっちから
一気に引きずり出しちゃる！
Let's drag them out using
creature detection jutsu!
母ちゃん
そうあんまり力入れんなや。
Ma, don't get so excited,
you'll get more wrinkles.
また小ジワが増えるで。
父ちゃんは黙っときんさい！
Just hush up, Pa!
しかし わしらを
呼んでまで何でそがなヤツと➡
But why go so far as to summon us
to fight this fellow, Jiraiya-boy?
自来也ちゃんが
やりあわにゃいけんのなら？
わしのかつての教え子でしてのぉ。
He happens to be
a former student of mine...
そんなヤツがおったとは
聞いとらんぞ！
We never knew you had one!
Then is he...?
ほんなら ソイツも…。
そう…。
Yes...
((自来也 : お呼びで？
As summoned.
Ah, good. I'm glad you've come!
(大ジジ様)ほほぉ
よう来た よう来た。
自来也ちゃんよ 大ジジ様は
お前の夢を見られたんじゃ。
Jiraiya-boy.
The Great Lord Elder had
a dream about you.
お前も知ってのとおり
これは予言じゃ。
As you are aware, it is a prophecy.
心して聞け。
はい。
So listen carefully.
Yes, sir!
では 伝える。
わしの夢では エロいだけのお主も➡
I shall now tell you. In my dream...
You, who are solely pervy, will still
manage to become a splendid ninja.
いずれ 立派な忍になる。
そして 一人前に
弟子を持つことになるのじゃが➡
And in time, you will have
your own disciple...
その弟子は 将来 忍の世に
大きな変革をもたらす忍になる。
That disciple will become a ninja
who will bring about a great change
to the ninja world.
That is what I saw in my dream.
夢では そう見えた。
変革？
A great change?
世に それまでにない
安定をもたらすか➡
Either great stability or great destruction.
(破滅をもたらすか…
そのどちらかの変革じゃ))
The likes of which this world
has never seen before.
One of those two.
予言の子か！
なら なんで お前が戦う!?
The child of the prophecy?!
Then why are you fighting him?
どうやら 正しい方向には
成長しなかったようでしての。
It seems he did not grow up
in the right direction.
それに… すでに 死んだ と
聞かされてまして…。
And when I heard he had died...
この子ではない と
思い込んでました。
I thought he couldn't have been
the one.
どちらにしろ 正しくなけりゃ
殺さにゃいけん。
In any case, if he is not righteous,
you must kill him.
まぁ あの予言は
大ボケジジイの戯れ言じゃ。
Well, that senile old man probably
made up that prophecy.
気にするな！ ほんなら いくで！
Don't worry about it!
All right let's do it!
見つけたで！
Found him!
速い！
It's fast!
捕まえたで！
Gotcha!
とりゃっ！
There we go!
父ちゃん！
おう！
Pa!
I'm on it!
あれが 輪廻眼か。
That's the Rinnegan?
たしかに 伝説に聞く眼と
同じじゃのう。
It certainly looks like the one mentioned
in the legend.
(フカサク)イヤな眼じゃ。
この子が あの予言の子だとはの。
What nasty eyes...
I can't believe he's that child of prophecy.
((大ジジ様 : お主は
その変革者を導く者じゃ。
You will guide that revolutionary.
いずれ お主には 大きな選択を
迫られるときがくるじゃろう。
The day will come when you will be forced
to make a critical selection.
選択？
Selection?
その選択次第で
世の変革が どちらに転ぶか➡
Your choice shall decide which way
the change goes.
(決まってしまうのじゃ))
《ガマ仙人よ… まさしく これが
選択のときですかの》
Great Lord Elder...
I wonder if this is
that moment of selection?
口寄せの術。
《今度は 人間の口寄せか》
お前は破滅をもたらす者だった。
ならば ここで倒すのが
師の役目だのぉ。
(エルザ)私は
仲間を守れる力があれば➡
それだけでいい。
その力と引き換えならば➡
私は 誰より弱くていい。
矛盾… してるな。
(アズマ)おもしろいヤツだ。
お前とは
正々堂々やりたかったね。
どういう意味だ？
時間切れということさ。